Everyone once again welcome
through this video we are going to understand how to put
multiple photos in a single frame
means you have multiple images
here, how can multiple images be put in a single frame
and
along with this how can slide be slowed down with the images,
we will see all this here,
see multiple image
means here that like here I have
taken an image and what to do with this image,
multiple frames have been applied here in a single
frame, so
how can we do it in this way, apart from this if
we talk about slide show here,
you can see the slide show here, like
I have a lot of these images and
as soon as I click on it, on
clicking, see a button
comes here, as I press this button,
my images keep getting
slideshowed here, so
how can you do this slide show, with the
help of open and through this particular video of today,
we are going to know here,
so let's start it  And let's understand this a little bit.
We will have to take it step by step here only
then it will be finished. So
I will explain it to you in detail.
See here, first of all what we have to do is to
import the open and module here. So
let's understand this a little bit. Here
I will take you to a
file of speaking where we are going to reduce all this with the help of open and.
Now see
what we will do first of all, we will
also import the module from open and
after that we are going to reduce all this.
See, first of all I will see
how a single image can be shown here.
First of all we will see that. Then we will see
how multiple images can be shown within a single frame.
See, first of all
I would like to talk about how a single image can be
shown.
We have already made a particular video of it where we have to
show the image and
close the frame of the image which is being formed.
We have made a particular dedicated video on it.
You can watch that video.
You will get the link of it through the i button or through the link inside the description.
Now let's talk about
how we can bring multiple images inside this frame. So for
that,
first of all I am going to import
cv2 here so that I can reduce it on the open frame
and next here I am going to need to
import name pi. See
why I am using the name pi.
You will get to know after a while why I have used the
length. So here in nmap
I create an alias with the
name mp and then run it. So
we will need both these modules here.
When we reduce
multiple images on a single frame here, first I will put
a single image here. To
put a single image, first of all I will have to
read out the image. So first of all I will
create a variable here
through which what will I do? Here, to
read the image through cv2,
we are going to call the I am read function here.
Here I am
read which is our function through which we will
read out the image file, we will
put it here. Let me bring the image
here.  So I will take this direction finding
image here.
For this, I will go to its properties and
copy this entire area. Now I am
copying this complete area here
because the reason is that my piping
file and my image are both
in different folders. So
what do I have to do here? I will have to
give the complete address of the image here. So I have
given this address. After that, what is the name of my image? If
you have a four-sided image, I will
copy this as well and close it.
After this, I will put a backward slash and
then the name of the image.
Currently, if you put this image forward like this, that is, if you
take it like this, then
it will not be able to accept your information.
Because of the slash here,
you will have to make it a relative path. So
for that, you have to put R. This
image of yours has been read.
After the image is read, what do you have to do
now? If you want, you can show this image.
So
what do you have to do to show the image
and you un dot here
what do you have is the I am show function yes with the help of I am show
function you can show the image
inside it first of all you have to
give the name of the frame which you are
putting here like I will give you a
small example like if I talk about this image, if I
open this image
then a frame opens with me, the
super name inside the frame is written img.4
this is your name so you have to
give this name of the frame here so right now I am going to
give the name of the frame and
see the frame we are reducing for that time so
I am giving the frame here and after that I will give the image here
what will it do to my image it will show now my
image is shown
after showing we have the next thing that the frame of the image should
close
after how much time it should close so
you will have to give that also or
when you press any button here the image should close
so you can give that also here
For that I will use CBT dot here.
What can I do with the wait key? For our image, the
shoulder level
frame that you have will open. We are going to close that frame. So
if I pass 0 here,
what will it do to us?
On pressing any button, it will stop. Your window should close. So
for the window to close, what will you have to do?
You will have to do destroy all
windows. Now
what is the difference between these? Destroy all windows and
destroy windows. This is the rate
video of the car. So if you
run it from there, here, see, I have an
image below. As soon as I open it,
see, my image has been created. Now one thing
I would like to tell you here is that the
size of this image, you see, the size of this image is
very large because
its pixels are very high.
Because of this, my frame is
not getting completed in the frame,
whereas I open it directly here.
If I open it directly here, then
this  The image comes completely
inside this frame, this is
because what they have done is they have
recised it, so in today's topic
we are going to talk about recise first,
how can you recise your image
because see one image here and
one image here, inside this you will
see here that your frame is complete,
your image inside the frame has
not come complete, they have kept this image
only half here, here the image that was supposed to
come to you till here has come
because the regulation of your image is
very high, so right now if I
close this image and close this too, then
how can this image be recised, first we will
talk about that, so the image has to be recised, so
before showing your image,
what should you do to recise your image, to recise
first you can create a separate variable of your own
or
you can resize it inside the same variable, so
here I am going to say I.M.G., that is, of the same variable  I am doing
recise inside, if you want you
can make it available separately, let me
show you by creating a separate variable here, so
I mean recise, here I am
creating a variable by the name of img,
through which first of all I will call cv2 dot here
we have a function named recise,
I will call it inside the recise function,
first of all you have to give which
image of yours that you want to recise, so
here I have my image A inside the img,
see here we have the img in which
our image A is, I have
given it here in recise, secondly
you have to give here with and height, means
how many with you should have, how much should your
height be, you can decide that,
so I would like to keep 500 here again
and the height of 300, ok give
with and height, I will keep 500 or 300 here,
now we will have to change this image that is given inside this image and
I will have to give the recise image here, let me do
this  As soon as I run it, you will see that my
image has changed here. You
can see here that its width is 500 Å
and its height is how many Å you have, it is
300 Å. Now this image which has been
measured, that is, your image has been measured, has been measured
from this particular point to the middle of this particular point
where my arrow is moving,
see, from here it has
gone to the middle of this arrow by touching it, so now I have an image of 500*300 pixels. For
now, I will close this image
and my image is quite good here, so let's
increase it a little, that is,
without increasing your width, let's
increase its height, so I will make the height 800. So
see, I have an
image and 800 has become a very big image
here, so instead of this, I will make
it 700 here and I will end it, so this is a
good image, right now you  If you want, you
can increase its weight a little more and
recharge it according to your requirement. So this will be
how we recise our image.
After resizing, now our next
topic here is that within a single frame,
as I am giving you as an example,
so let's understand how you can keep multiple images within a single frame. So
see, if
you want to keep multiple images within an image, then first of all you have to
create a multiple array of the image that you have received. Now
how will this array be created? Let's talk about its value. So
your array should be created in such a way that
first a block will be created. Inside that block,
you will get two images like this. That means
basically you will have two multiple arrays inside one array.
If I
show it as a small example by creating this arrow,
then you can create this arrow in such a way that
here I talk about
what I will create called V in
which NP dot I will use the array function here
so that it becomes clear to you that
what kind of an array we need.  You have to do Erikson with the
help of which your image will
come to you like this, so for this,
first of all what will I do, here I
create a bracket and inside it I
create another bracket, inside it I will say van
2, van 1 2, now what is this van you,
we will understand this now, after that this
image is created, then van you have van you,
again van you have van you and after that
I will talk about it, so this way your
channel will be created, then you will have
multiple images inside a single frame,
now what is this van and you and what is this van and you, so
basically you have a particular
image, the
RGB colors that are running inside that image, those pixels of color are
represented here, now what are these pixels
and how are they read out here, let's
understand this here, so for that
I will
take the function I read which you have here again
and the image that is inside it,
we print this image, that means print
off here  But I do IMG here and
print and run IMG. So
look at your image, for example, I open your image
once here
on the left side so that it becomes clear to you
what I am going to understand. Like this is my image.
Here, if we talk about this image, then
what do you have inside this image? It is
divided pixel by pixel.
Inside it, a small pixel is formed, then
after that a small pixel, inside that a
small pixel is formed. All the
colour combinations that are being formed in all these small pixels are
given to you here. Look, the
first bracket starts from here till here. If we
talk about the second bracket, then it starts from
here till here. If we talk about the third bracket, then it starts from here till here. So, in the
video that you saw before this, you must have
noticed one thing. When I
told you about colour, then you have one colour.
Grace, one of these is RGB. In it, there are
three primary colours, which are red, green and blue.
We have those three primary colours.  What do
you have with regard to colours,
any image is prepared with you, like I
am talking about this image here,
what do you have inside it, all the colours are made by mixing three primary colours
here, so the
combinations of RGB colour
can be seen here, so
what do you have, R is here, these are your R
colour combinations, after that, you will have the
combinations of B colour here
and what do you have, the
combinations of green colour, now how is this combination
arrangement, so this is what you are going to
understand in a better way in the upcoming video,
how can you make a layering by making these combinations
and how do you
create this image by making them, so you will get to see all these things
here in the upcoming video, so
for now, just
see here how the colours are going into the images that you have here,
now here you have a
matrix, how is it being created in this way,
see what you have here  What is happening is
a completely array of an image being formed.
An array has already been formed with you. Here, it is
complete,
inside which you will be able to see from here till here, you have an
arrow of complete images, meaning that
your image is
divided into numbers.
We had understood this thing in our previous video that
if you take a year of that image and
see its pixels, then what do we
do is represent it in a matrix
so that we can see the colour inside it,
which colour, how is the
RGB colour being formed,
we will also be able to see that thing here.
What is happening inside your image, a
matrix is ​​being formed.
What do we have to do with this matrix is ​​to join it with the second matrix,
then what do we have to do
with the third matrix, what do we have to do
with the fourth matrix, so overall,
this 1 2, this is
one channel that you have, or else we will reduce it by one.  If I
tell you in a better way, then I will take 1 2 3 and then I will take van you
three, then after that I will put
1 2 3 and then here you will put common
123 then do it, so look at this,
what is van you three here, so this
1 2 3 you have the RGB colour here, the
colour here, the RGB colour that is
going on with you, here it has
a channel of RGB colour, the second
RGB colour is water, this channel that is visible is
your channel of one image, this is the
channel of the second image, so this is yours,
what will you see within one row, you will see two images,
you want to see up and down and
multiple images, so for that
what will you have to do, you will have to do one channel of RGB channel, you will have to
see the second channel of RGPV channel, then you will have
two layers created here,
now if you want, you can create more than two layers
here, so now let us see it in a little
more detail, how
can this be created.  So let me
copy it back here,
do it once because I am going to need all of this, so
I have taken this, now let me
change the image a little inside it, I
reduce the image, you can take any image from it,
like I take this,
here I will take the image of Img5,
right, I am taking this, so
taking the date property, I am going to
take the second email here, now if you want, you can
also recise its image,
no, you cannot recise the image or
it reduces, I am just taking six,
so let me reduce it,
Img6, because the width of this is
less and the height is
more, so whenever you are trying to
put multiple images here in a single frame,
then at that time you have to keep this thing in
mind that you must recise the image
because all these images will be recised together, then
they will come to you comfortably in a particular frame, so that's why
you
must recise the image, so I have done this
exercise here  But
I have the image and the recise image
ready as a regi image. Now first of all I will
tell you
how to put multiple images within a single row.
Now as I said, you have
two matrices here. Here this is a
matrix here and this is a matrix here.
So I have to join the two matrices and
prepare a single matrix here.
Then I have to combine the matrix here. And to
combine the matrix,
we have the step and the
stack function here. Today we have the style function
number which does what it does to you. It
combines the horizontal
and the vertical and then after that it gives a new
aeration. So for that only,
what are we going to do here? We are going to use number.
Let's understand
here how it is being created. Okay, so for
this, first of all you are
getting some detailed information about nampai.
You can do the basic course here
so that it will be beneficial for you that
we can learn which function of the bike.  We are doing that,
let's do it first of all I am doing it
here by joining your two horizontal images,
I will tell you here, so here we have to
join two horizontal images,
so for that I am creating a variable named h here,
inside that I am going to use np
done yes np dot I will use the h step
here here i
what am going to do here, I am going to
create a new image by joining the two horizontal images that you have here, so
what are we going to do through this type, I am going to
join both of them together, that
means I am going to join the two images here,
let's
see it a little practical once,
after that we will be able to move forward inside it
so that it is clear to you here what we are going to do
here, so see I am doing
this here, it is
okay here I will also keep telling you a little about nampai
that in this way our number is going to
decrease, so you reduce one, the
number will come first, you can watch the video of one comfortably
so that you also  If there is benefit then
andp dot I will do it here yes and
I will have to give a bracket inside it here
then c com of v here I will have to
give it like this as soon as I run it,
see your 1 2 3 4 1 2 3 you have got
date van you three what is yours
and van you three is one more so what has it done, it has
joined the two Erics together immediately so we also want something like this so
let me do it here
inside adjust today I go inside stock where do I have an
error here so
underscore image yes are you underscore the image you have here you have one that is
hey then after that underscore
you have another image I will take them and
I will show the image here so
as soon as I show it here but
we have here till now I
take this image after that inside I am show
I will have to pass this h
inside which my horizontal images are joining each other
I have
recised here  By recise I have
reduced everything and inside this I make it a little
smaller, that means I make its size
a little smaller, so basically talking about
this, the height is long and the
image that you have is big in size here,
so I make it 300 here
and keep it around 500 here and as soon as
I run,
see, I have two images here within the same frame
and how are both these
images, you have a horizontal
arrangement, if I have to make this image
vertical, then I will use
C stag here, let's try vertical here
quickly, so to make vertical,
what am I going to do here, I will
put V here and by
putting V I will do vertical strike, that
means C you have, I will create a variable here and
P dot here, I am going to use C stack
here, through this I am going to
give both the images inside it
which we need, so one is we have
R only  Give underscore images, secondly we
again have underscore images and
next here what do I have to pass in place of h, I
have to pass v and
as soon as I run it, see,
both my images will be visible to you.  These are already
joined vertically with you. Now I want all these
four to merge together to
form a new image which has four images inside it. You
can also put more than four images. It is
not necessary that you have four
images here. If you want to bring five images in one frame, then
you can arrange it as you wish. I
just
want to arrange both the images in the same frame. So
I took the horizontal and the vertical. Now
first of all, see, you have got the horizontal images
and you will have to reduce the size of the images a bit. So,
I will keep its weight and width as 300
and what will I do with the height, I will make it
300 here. That means a 300 * 300
image will be fine. Now first of all, what will I
do, I will arrange both of them for the horizon. That
means these images of yours will be made
horizontal. Then
we are going to arrange those horizontal images vertically.
So, to arrange them vertically.
What do I have to do here,
this horizontal image will have to be
given H and S, meaning one layer after that
we will have to give the second layer in this way, so
I am giving layer by layer here and
after that I have put totally C here
and as soon as I do it, see,
I have to make only one frame, how many images do I have added
here, if we talk about it, then one frame has been added
in four, now I would like to add one
more layer here in this way,
so what will I do here, I will
go inside the image and put the date common and here
inside the horizontal I have added one more image,
here I keep only two verticals, let's
run here, so see, in this way
your number of images is being created, then you can
increase the number of images as much as you want,
you
can increase it in this way, so in this way
what do you have, inside a frame now you
can give multiple images here,
now let's talk about the next topic here,
inside the next topic
what do we have to do, we have to run the slide show, like
see, we have one image,
This feature is present inside the image, what do you do with it,
inside it you can
run a slide show of multiple images here, like if you have
many images, I want
my slide suite to run in this way, so
you can run this slide show,
what are we going to do to run this resource,
first of all we have to open here, for this,
first of all what do we have to do here, we will
need the OS model, so I am
importing here and I am importing
OS, why did I input OS model now
because there is a reason behind it
here because our folder is a
different folder and
inside it you have multiple files, so
I need the names of all those files,
with the help of the operating system model only we
can get all the names of its files,
let's get them first, how
can the name be got, so I am going to get
all those names by using the OS model here, so
a
list will be ready for that, so I take the list underscore
name, all these names of the
images are going to come to us and for that OS
dot is here  But we have a function named list directory with the
help of which we can get the
names of all the files that you have read in that particular folder.
Today we will unlist it and which is our folder. So
this is the folder that we have. The
data from here to here is in our folder. So
this is our folder.
Here our complete folder is ready and the
list stem is ready inside it and I am
printing the names of the list here.
These list names are ready in which
you will be able to see the image one image two image three image four image six
images are big
and if you see here also then you have 6 images
ready. Now what you have to do is to
run the slide show. Now
what should it mean?
Each image should come to me automatically and
we have to show the images of the APK. Basically,
for each image to come to you, what you will do here is
fold it and do it
through poll. You can get each image one by one. And then
after that you can do it.
So I am going to use the for
loop here and the for loop also
what for you have the name here means
you will get the name of the list here date
name and here in 4 in 4 in and
from whom will you get the list directors here
so I am going to get the list here the list
names which we have created here
now
what is going to come to us through this it is not going to come one by one
now what are those names image one image two
image three image four stars will
come and I have to give the name of the complete address of the data that we have here
inside I am showing so
basically I need the path here and I
also need the path plus name here so I
need two things here so I am going to create the path and path plus name
here let's
understand how it is created so
first of all I create the path here and
how will it be created with us so here is the
path we have now this path that you are seeing
we have given it directly so we are
giving the reference path here
If we are not giving the path directly, we are doing it by
joining, then
what should you do with these slashes that are being formed, should
you make them double slashes because the
reason behind this is because black N means
new line black and short B
means bold and you have
many more, what do you have,
special sequences are running, so now these
sequences that are running,
we have to remove these sequences and instead of this we have to slice all the places, so
what should you do, if you
apply backward slash and slash twice, then you will
see a slash here, so this is done with
us, now what we have to do,
we have to prepare the complete name here,
which we have to give inside the list, in which
we have to show the image, so now I
am going to prepare IMG underscore sleep here,
how will it be prepared with path, so for you
first of all I have to give the pad
with the path, I have to add it with a slash and
after that whatever the name of the list is, you will
have to give it, so I will use your double slash here.  I am going to do it,
then after that I will
do plus again and the name that you have inside it, that
means the list which is
not marked one by one inside, has come to us, so
inside the name IMG, I have that
completely path with name ready, now
I have to show my image, so for that I will do
cvtu.im show here,
first I will do I am read, so what will be my image,
so I did I am read
and inside I am read I will have to
give the number of the image, I will have to give the image name, so
I gave the image name here,
what happened with the image name, I have got the image,
now I will show all of them inside the same frame,
because some image is big,
some image is small, then how good it will be if all of them are kept inside the same frame, so
we will bring all these images in the same frame, so
for this I am
creating a variable by the name of IMG small MG
and inside this image I will do here, I will
recise it, so cb2 dot here we will use
it
and through rec we will make our image
and for that I am IMG  Yes and let's say now
I will have to fix the size of all of them, so
see some are tall among us, which means some of us have
more height and some have more wither, so let's keep the
height and wither the same
and let me go up once and see
how much has been kept at the top, I had
kept it 500 * 700 here,
in which our images came out good, so
what am I doing here this time also, I will make it 500 *
600, I will
not keep it too big, let's make it 500600, here
you will get a good image here
or this one will be 500 * 600, okay
what will happen to our image after it is recised, now
what you have to do is show the image, so to show
it, dot here, I am
you have a show function, we will use it here
and I am inside show, I am,
first of all you have to give the
name of your window, what is the name of the window,
after that I will give our
image here, so inside I am, our image is
Now what do we need, here we
need the wait key, if we wait here for how much
time, means if we
want to run it automatically here or if we
want to do it manualism, then we will have to give that, so
for that I will
use the wait key here at w tu dot here and
through the wait key I will extract it here, means I will
give the instruction that after how much time should it
repeat here, let's do two or one reduction,
first let's run it automatically, then
after that on pressing the button how will the
image go to the next, let's see that as well,
so for running it automatically I will have to
give the time here, so I am giving the time of five seconds for
one image to run here,
now after the image is completely run, all
my images, all the windows
should get destroyed, so
what will I need for that, for that
I will need your
CBT here, destroy all windows, so
I have to use cbt.wister all windows.
Ok, this list has come to you and
through this list only we are going to do a reduction here, let's do a
reduction here,
I will put the list name inside it
so that there is no confusion and it never stops with you, let's
run it here, take an image,
after 5 seconds your
image will change,
ok, so let's do a reduction, this
time is taking a lot of time, the
images were coming very slow, so I will make
it a bit faster, I will give it a
time of one second, within one second,
my hundred images
should keep running here, right, so let's
see it here and I will run it once
again, see,
within 1 second, multiple images will
keep coming to me here and it will stop here automatically,
right, it is running like this,
but now I want that I
press any button here and on pressing that button, the
images should keep running, so
for that, what are we going to do, we will
pass Jio inside it here  Because
what does zero do to you, it
works on any key of your keyboard and when I
run it, see
my first image, if I press the arrow,
my second image will appear, I will go to the second key, then I will go
back here, so
what do you have here, the
images keep moving from front to front, so in the
same way you have fixed it, the orange key is there,
see in this way the image you have
moved forward, right, so in this way you
can run a slide show inside your image here, so I think I hope you must have understood
what to do with the help of which code, so first of all
what did we learn, how to show the image
basically and after that
how can we create multiple images
here within the same directory, that is, within the same directory, and next we get to know
how to run slice suit inside the images, for
now that's all for today's video, we will see
you with our next video, until then stay with us like this,
tel dan  Then Good Bye
[Applause]
[Music]